<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stefan Gloutnikov</title>
    <link>https://gloutnikov.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stefan Gloutnikov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 12:14:52 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gloutnikov.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dataset Release: Six Years of SiriusXM Now Playing Data</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/dataset-sxm-nowplaying-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 12:14:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/dataset-sxm-nowplaying-v1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Sirius XM &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sgloutnikov/sxm-tracker&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;now playing tracker&lt;/a&gt; has been running for six years without any major interruptions. Today I gathered all of the data collected to date, and am open sourcing the dataset for anyone can use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Print on Your Old Printer from Any Client on Your Home Network</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/raspberry-pi-print-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 13:34:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/raspberry-pi-print-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are like me, you may have an old, but still perfectly functioning printer which you would like to print on from anywhere in your house. In my case, I even kept an old Windows PC just for printing. That PC is soon going to recycling, now that a Raspberry Pi helped make the printer reachable from any computer, phone, or tablet on the home network. This post will show how to easily achieve this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Apache Pulsar on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/getting-started-with-pulsar-on-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 01:29:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/getting-started-with-pulsar-on-k8s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apache Pulsar is a distributed pub-sub messaging system that I have recently enjoyed testing for some projects of mine. It has grown very much on me and am now preferring it over Apache Kafka. In this post we will go over installing and getting started with an Apache Pulsar instance running on Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Session Window(s) SQL Query</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/time-series-windows-sql-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 14:46:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/time-series-windows-sql-query/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back I needed to identify time windows within a time series dataset which led me to discover some interesting SQL functions I was not aware of. In short, what I refer to as a window is a start and end timestamp during which certain defined conditions were true. This post will explore a bit more of the problem definition and go over an example SQL query to tackle it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GraphQL Subscriptions with Go (gqlgen) Example</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/graphql-subscriptions-go-gqlgen-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 14:08:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/graphql-subscriptions-go-gqlgen-example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GraphQL subscriptions are extremely useful in situations when a server needs to update its clients. A chat application is a great example to demonstrate this, as when new messages arrive we want to distribute them among all chat participants as quickly as possible without polling. When I first started looking at implementing GraphQL subscriptions in Go it took me a bit before I had my aha moment and everything clicked together. Also, at that time there were not a whole lot of examples that I could look at or reference. This post will go over a concrete chat application example using GraphQL subscriptions and a backend built in Go with gqlgen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 10:54:48 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/quotes/</guid>
      <description>My absolute favorite to kick off this list:
&amp;ldquo;There are only two hard things in Computer Science: cache invalidation and naming things.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ndash; Phil Karlton
later evolved to
&amp;ldquo;There are two hard things in Computer Science: cache invalidation, naming things, and off-by-one errors.&amp;rdquo;
If you are wondering how naming things could be hard, I suggest checking out these posts [0] [1].
&amp;ldquo;A complex system that works is invariably found to have evolved from a simple system that worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic Programmer Tips</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/pragmatic-programmer-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 21:57:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/pragmatic-programmer-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite software engineering books recently released a new edition and has been an absolute pleasure to read again. &lt;a href=&#34;https://pragprog.com/titles/tpp20/the-pragmatic-programmer-20th-anniversary-edition/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Pragmatic Programmer&lt;/a&gt; is back with a 20th-anniversary edition and a fresh look at the modern software development landscape.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevent your Apple ID from constantly getting locked</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/prevent-appleid-from-constantly-getting-locked/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 17:29:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/prevent-appleid-from-constantly-getting-locked/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are like me, and have all of your Apple devices constantly prompt you for your Apple ID password only to inform you that your Apple ID is locked, here is something that you could do to prevent it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying and Graphing Missing Time Series Data with Apache Spark and Highcharts</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/identifying-and-graphing-missing-timeseries-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/identifying-and-graphing-missing-timeseries-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When performing my analysis and graphing for my previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://gloutnikov.com/post/sxm-theheat-analysis/&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; I ran into a problem of identifying and displaying missing time series data. From a series of data that occurs daily, I wanted to identify if there were missing days, and to graph them so that they can easily be seen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing SiriusXM&#39;s The Heat &#34;Now Playing&#34; Data with Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/sxm-theheat-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 16:02:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/sxm-theheat-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My SiriusXM tracker for &amp;lsquo;The Heat&amp;rsquo; radio station has now been running since the summer of 2016 and has collected a good amount of data. It seemed like a great opportunity to make use of this data for getting some insight into what songs/artists/albums have been popular throughout the months, and also get some Spark practice under my belt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Apache Spark with MongoDB</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/using-spark-with-mongodb-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 15:40:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/using-spark-with-mongodb-example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This example will go over setting up a simple Scala project in which we will access a Mongo Database and perform read/write operations. In order to access MongoDB from spark we will need the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mongodb.com/products/spark-connector&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MongoDB Connector for Spark&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaadin Spring and Spring Boot - Reload UI changes without server restarts in IntelliJ IDEA</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/vaadin-ui-refresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 21:19:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/vaadin-ui-refresh/</guid>
      <description>After having worked with GWT several years ago and really liking the framework, I recently found myself trying out Vaadin for a hobby application I want to develop. Vaadin and GWT have their similarities and differences. One of the differences is that Vaadin runs its application logic on the server side, unlike GWT which runs on the client side. This calls for some little extra setup required in the IDE in order to run the application and be able to instantly see UI changes in your browser while developing, without having to restart the application server every time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host your own Heroku with Dokku on DreamHost&#39;s Cloud</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/host-your-own-heroku/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 21:06:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/host-your-own-heroku/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After hosting a few of my apps on Heroku I quickly became a fan of the platform, and saw why it gets such high praise. The ease of deploying an application straight through Git is amazing. Not having to worry about managing servers, or managing the environment is perfect&amp;ndash;it allows a developer to go straight into developing and deploying their apps with minimal hassle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control your Homebrew package upgrades</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/control-homebrew-upgrades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 12:55:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/control-homebrew-upgrades/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always upgraded my installed homebrew packages whenever updates became available. Recently however, I ran into a situation where I did not want to upgrade a specific package while also upgrading the rest. Loved how incredibly easy Homebrew made this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Projects</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 23:22:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>NeterraProxy On-demand m3u8 playlist/playback daemon for Neterra.tv, running on Android.
SiriusXM: The Heat Tracker &amp;amp; The Highway Tracker Tracks songs played on SiriusXM&amp;rsquo;s The Heat R&amp;amp;B and Hip-Hop station. Displays top played statistics and new songs. Python, MongoDB, Django. [Blog] [Tracker] [Web Client]
Bulsatcom Fire TV Application Amazon Fire TV application for watching the Bulgarian TV provider Bulsatcom. The official and incompatible touch apps for Android and iOS were used to reverse engineer the APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SiriusXM: The Heat Tracker</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/theheat-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 19:14:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/theheat-tracker/</guid>
      <description>There are a few SiriusXM stations that I always listened to in my car. With Hip-Hop being one of my favorite genres, The Heat was one of my favorite stations. I liked that they play new and old songs, and I would always pick up on some new song that is beginning to trend. After moving to Bulgaria I lost this ability, and I could not justify paying more for online radio than Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 15:08:16 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>I was born in the town of Gabrovo, located in north-central Bulgaria, where I lived throughout my early childhood before my family moved to the United States. I received a B.S. and a M.S. in Computer Science from San José State University. The areas that I am most passionate about are in distributed systems, anything related to working with data, information security, and machine learning. I’m a big sports fan, and watch a fair bit of TV series&amp;ndash;probably more than I should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World! From Hugo</title>
      <link>https://gloutnikov.com/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 12:56:44 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gloutnikov.com/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>First post from Hugo&amp;ndash;the fast and modern static website engine.
I quickly become a fan of statically generated sites after seeing Jekyll a few years ago. After getting tired of WordPress, it was on my radar to update my site to a statically generated one, and learn something new at the same time. I was not a fan of the installation dependencies I had to manage with Jekyll, but yesterday I stumbled upon a HN post about Hugo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
